<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The noble souldier's answer to Mr. Walker's speech, in London-Derry, before the last fight</title>
            <author>Noble souldier.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1689</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 4 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 2 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-12">2011-12 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A52384</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing N1216A</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R370</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">12495798</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 12495798</idno>
            <idno type="VID">62498</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A52384)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 62498)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 769:40)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The noble souldier's answer to Mr. Walker's speech, in London-Derry, before the last fight</title>
                  <author>Noble souldier.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([2] p.)   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed for J.W. ...,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1689.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>Broadside.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in Huntington Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Walker, George, 1645?-1690.</term>
               <term>Ireland --  History --  War of 1689-1691.</term>
               <term>Broadsides --  England --  London --  17th century</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-07</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-07</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-08</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-08</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-06</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="letter">
            <pb facs="tcp:62498:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <head>The Noble SOULDIER's Anſwer TO Mr. Walker's Speech, IN LONDON-DERRY, Before the laſt FIGHT.</head>
            <opener>
               <salute>Most Noble and Victorious Governour,</salute>
            </opener>
            <p>I Proſtrate my ſelf at your Feet, in behalf of my ſelf, and the reſt of my Fellow Souldiers, who are all willing to venture our Lives, and all that is dear to us, in Defence of the Proteſtant Religion, King <hi>William</hi> and Queen <hi>Mary,</hi> this <hi>Place,</hi> and your <hi>Self;</hi> whoſe moſt Noble Courage, Wiſe Conduct, Great Succeſs, Divine Orations, Courteous and Obliging Kindneſs, hath Infus'd into each of us the Hearts of Ten. And You, moſt Valiant Sir, have exceeded all the great Heroes of our Times: Nay, we cannot compare you to none but a ſecond <hi>Sampſon,</hi> a <hi>Goliah,</hi> a <hi>Hannibal,</hi> a <hi>Scipio,</hi> or rather a <hi>Tamberlain,</hi> who with but a poor handful of Men, did vanquiſh and overcome Armies that were innumerable. So when we conſider of the ſmall quantity of Men we are to our Enemies, we cannot but be aſtoniſh'd and amaz'd at the over-ruling Providence of the Almighty, <hi>who hath led us out to Battel,</hi> and given us ſuch unheard of Victories over our Idola<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trous Enemies. And now, moſt Dear Sir, We are again to Encounter our Inhumane Foes: Heaven and you, have whet and ſharpened the Teeth of our Hearts and Souls againſt them; and if every Man had Ten Thou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſand Lives, we ſhould not grudge, but willingly Sacrifice them all for our Religion, You, and this Place. O with what amazing wonder do we think of their Barbarity! Here is ſcarce a Tree, Field, or Houſe, but are Witneſſes of their Cruelty! They have Painted our Houſes,
<pb facs="tcp:62498:2"/>Water'd our Gardens, Dung'd our Fields, and Colour'd our Rivers with the Bodies and Blood of our moſt Dear and Chriſtian Parents. And let us look back and behold the Maſſacres of <hi>Paris</hi> and <hi>Piedmont,</hi> as well as of this Kingdom; their Damnable Inquiſition, Worſhipping of Stocks, and Stones, Ridiculous Pagentry, Invocating Saints, pretended Miracles, Praying for the Dead, allowing common Harlots, Pardons, and many other Diabolical and Idolatrous Practices, not becoming Men profeſſing Chriſtianity. When we think of theſe their Principles and Practices, we rather think them <hi>Turks</hi> than <hi>Chriſtians,</hi> and <hi>Devils</hi> than <hi>Men.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>And now again, Reverend and Renowned Sir, We are going to Engage the Enemy once more, Our Hearts Bleed within us to think of the Too Great Danger You Expoſe your Self to, and if you ſhould be Cut off (which we pray God to prevent) we are all loſt, and our Hearts will burſt our Bodies, and our very <hi>Souls will melt away with Heavineſs.</hi> Beſides, Sir, Your very Name is a Terror to them, and an Encouragement to us; and your looks, like <hi>Caeſars,</hi> overcome where ever you approach; Your preſervation, is ours; Your de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtruction, is ours. The greateſt of our Ambition is, to ſee You Live and be preſerved as the greateſt Miracle of our Age, for Valour, Conduct, Piety and Learning.</p>
            <p>To conclude, We Humbly beg your Pardon, for preſuming ſo much upon your Goodneſs and Patience; and beg of God to bleſs, keep, and preſerve you <hi>in the Day of Battle, and give us Victory over our Enemies.</hi> Which God Grant for his Son Chriſt Jeſus ſake, <hi>Amen.</hi>
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>
               <hi>London,</hi> Printed for <hi>J. W.</hi> in <hi>Ludgate-ſtreet.</hi> 1689.</p>
         </div>
         <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
